<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>manage on SQL by example</title><link>https://peyman.blog/sql/tags/manage/</link><description>Recent content in manage on SQL by example</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>slh.peyman@gmail.com (Peyman Salehi)</managingEditor><webMaster>slh.peyman@gmail.com (Peyman Salehi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 01:06:01 +0330</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peyman.blog/sql/tags/manage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create and Drop Table</title><link>https://peyman.blog/sql/posts/create-and-drop-table/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 01:06:01 +0330</pubDate><author>slh.peyman@gmail.com (Peyman Salehi)</author><guid>https://peyman.blog/sql/posts/create-and-drop-table/</guid><description>Create table By using CREATE TABLE statement you can create a new table.
-- Create a table called users CREATE TABLE users ( id SERIAL PRIMARY KEY, -- auto increment primary key, handles 1 to 2,147,483,647 -- Or use BIGSERIAL that handles from up to 9,223,372,036,854,775,807 first_name VARCHAR NOT NULL, -- varchar column that can&amp;#39;t be null last_name VARCHAR (255), created_at TIMESTAMP, -- without time zone, updated_at TIMESTAMP WITH TIME ZONE, -- or use timestamptz code INTEGER, rate double precision, -- double precision floating-point number active BOOLEAN DEFAULT true, -- boolean with default value of true group_id INTEGER NOT NULL, -- PRIMARY KEY (col1, col2), make col1 and col2 as primary key FOREIGN KEY (group_id) REFERENCES groups (group_id) -- set foreign key on another table ); PostgreSQL docs - create table</description></item><item><title>Create and Drop Database</title><link>https://peyman.blog/sql/posts/create-and-drop-database/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:50:10 +0330</pubDate><author>slh.peyman@gmail.com (Peyman Salehi)</author><guid>https://peyman.blog/sql/posts/create-and-drop-database/</guid><description>Create Database With CREATE DATABASE statement you can create a new database.
-- create a database called coffee CREATE DATABASE coffee; PostgreSQL docs
Remove database Use DROP DATABASE statement to remove a database.
-- drop a database called coffe DROP DATABASE coffee; -- Force to drop the database if anyone is connected to it DROP DATABASE coffee FORCE; -- Doesn&amp;#39;t thorw an error if database doesn&amp;#39;t exist DROP DATABASE IF EXISTS coffee; PostgreSQL docs</description></item></channel></rss>